اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ۝بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ۝
اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرا
The first verses revealed to Rasool Allah ﷺ were, the verses of Surah Al-Alaq(سورة العلق),
the first verses of Surah Al-Alaq(سورة العلق).
اِقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ۝خَلَقَ الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ عَلَقٍ۝
اقْرَأْ وَرَبُّكَ الْأَكْرَمُ۝الَّذِي عَلَّمَ بِالْقَلَمِ۝عَلَّمَ الْإِنْسَانَ مَا لَمْ يَعْلَمْ۝
These are the first Ayaat(آيات) that were revealed.
After that the revelation stopped for a while.
And the whole initial encounter of Rasool Allah ﷺ with revelation plus the waiting period that followed it,
was to make Rasool Allah ﷺ love the revelation and miss it.
And it is to leave permanent marks on him, or a permanent impression on him ﷺ.
Because we mentioned that the manner in which the revelation occurred.
Rasool Allah ﷺ was squeezed, and the same command was repeated three times.
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ had to wait and he was missing the revelation so much.
There's a narration Bukhari(بخاريْ) that Rasool Allah ﷺ, he missed the revelation so much
that he would go to a top of a mountain and attempt suicide.
The first Ayaat(آيات) that were revealed after Al-Alaq(ألعلق),
were the Ayaat(آيات) from Surah(سورة) Al-Muzzammil(المزمل) and Sura Al-Mudassir(سورت المدثر).
Now there's a difference of opinion on which was the first
but there is an agreement that these were the second and third set of Ayaat(آيات)
even though we don't know, which one of them was second or third.
So, you have the Ayaat(آيات) of Surah Al-Alaq(سورة العلق),
and then you have the Al-Ayaat(آيات) of Al-Muzammil(المزمل), and Ayaat(آيات) of Al-Muddassir(المدثر).
These Ayaat(آيات), one can say that they form manual book for the Dai'yah(داعيه), the one, who was calling to Islam.
And we can summarize it in Iqra'a(إقْرَاء), Qumm(قُمْ), Qumm(قُمْ).
And you can remember this, Iqra'a(إقْرَاء), Qumm(قُمْ), Qumm(قُمْ),
These were the first Ayaat(آيات) to train the early Muslims in Da'wah(دعوة).
Iqra'a(إقْرَاء), Qumm(قُمْ), Qumm(قُمْ).
Iqra'a(اقراء):
اِقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ۝ خَلَقَ الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ عَلَقٍ۝
Qumm: (قُمْ)
يَا أَيُّهَا الْمُزَّمِّلُ۝قُمِ اللَّيْلَ إِلَّا قَلِيلًا۝
And then other Qumm: (قُمْ) is:
يَا أَيُّهَا الْمُدَّثِّرُ۝قُمْ فَأَنْذِرْ۝
So, you have Iqra'a(إقْرَاء)
which is command to recite and learn.
And then you have:
قُمِ اللَّيْلَ إِلَّا قَلِيلًا َ
Pray at night, and then you have:
قُمْ فَأَنْذِرْ۝
Stand up and warn.
So, the first thing is you learn and this is something that you can apply in yourself.
The first thing is you learn, you study, you gain knowledge in religion.
And then the next step is you apply this in yourself and you start preaching it to others.
قُمْ فَأَنْذِرْ۝
Warn, so what you learn you have to teach.
Ibn Al-Qayyim(ابن القيم) says that,
you don't attain complete Eeman(ايمان) until you go through the stages of learning and teaching
and propagating the message of Allahعَزّوجَلّ.
So, you have the first stage is Iqra'a(إقْرَاء) learning and then after that you start by teaching
قُمْ فَأَنْذِرْ۝
Stand up and warn
Now, learning and warning or teaching, need something else to go along with it.
And that is Ibadah(عباده), forms of Nawafil(نوافل) that you do, like Qiyaam-Ul-Lail(قيام اليل).
And Qiyaam-Ul-Lail(قيام اليل) was mandatory on the early Muslims.
Allahسبحانه وتعالى made it mandatory on the early Muslims for a few years and then that was abrogated.
And however with the situation of Rasool Allah ﷺ, he had to pray Qiyaam-Ul-Lail(قيام اليل) it was mandatory for him,
until he passed away, until he died,
Rasool Allah ﷺ was praying Qiyaam-Ul-Lail(قيام اليل) and it was mandatory on him.
So, here we have a complete program.
You have a program of learning, knowledge
and then a program of Daw'ah(دعوة), and a program of rituals of Ibadah(عبادة).
And they all complement each other and they all assist in building a complete Muslim personality.
The work of propagating and teaching could be draining on the heart
and without this element of Ibadah(عبادة), one standing up and praying to Allah سبحانه وتعالى, in the middle of the night
the heart could harshen and become rough.
So, this Qiyaam-Ul-Lail(قيام اليل) softens the heart
and it prepares the person for the rest of the day.
Such thing can also be said about Zikr(زكر),
Ibn Qayyim(ابن القيم), he talks about his Shaikh Ibn Taymiyyah(شيخ ابن تيميه).
He says that every day after Salaat-Ul-Fajr(صلاة الفجر), he would go out to the fields in the outskirts of Damascus.
And he would just sit there mentioning the name of Allah making Zikr(زكر) until sunrise.
So, we once told him, why do you do this on a daily basis.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) said: This is my breakfast, if I don't have it, my body will fail me.
This is food for my soul, it gives me energy for the rest of the day.
If I don't have this meal in the morning, I'm going to be weak for the rest of my day.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ was strengthened by this Ibadah(عبادة) of the Qiyaam-Ul-Lail(قيام اليل).
And it is also something that Allah made mandatory on the early Muslims,
because of the unique circumstances they went through,
the difficulties that they had to go through are more than anything else that the Ummah(امة) would face afterwards.
That's why they had to go through this intensive training.
Plus, they are the core group, they are the foundation of Islam.
Sahabah رضي الله عنهم are the generation, which Islam was built on, they are the ones who spread it,
and if you have like a tent, there's this pillar in the middle that holds the whole tent,
that is the Sahabah(صحابہ) for this religion, they were the foundation of this religion.
So, they had to be very strong, and that strength came from this intensive training program
that they went through in the early years of Makkah.
So, you had this core group which is small in number, we could say less than 100, who went through this training.
But then these people became so strong that wherever you could put them
you could immediately see the influence they have on the people surrounding them.
I mean, Al-Ansaar(الأنْصَار), for example, are late comers to Islam,
Al-Ansaar(الأنْصَار) only became Muslim, in the last half of the Da'wah(دعوة) of Rasool Allah ﷺ .
But because the Muhajireen(مهاجرين) came and lived with them, and mixed with them
and in the initial stage, Rasool Allah ﷺ made the Brotherhood.
you would have one Ansaari(أنصاري) and one Muhajir(مهاجر), and they were brothers.
This gave a chance for the Muhajireen(مهاجرين) to help the Ansaar(أنصار) in the religious aspect
and the Ansaar(أنصار) helped the Muhajireen(مهاجرين) in the financial support and the social support that they needed.
But the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم the early Sahabah(صحابہ),
the Muhajireen(مهاجرين) had this light in them that would emanate and affect the whole surrounding, around them.
So, we have Iqra'a(إقْرَاء), Qumm(قُمْ), Qumm(قُمْ), and remember these three words.
What was the response of the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) to the Da'wah(دعوة) of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
They responded in various different ways.
And some of them were at different times, and some of them might have been stages.
But these are the different responses that the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), showed towards the message of Muhammadﷺ.
And there's a list of them we'll start talking about them right now but I'll just go through the list.
And Number one, mockery,
Number two, insulting and harming the Messenger,
Number three, accusations or character assassination.
Number four, deforming or defaming the message.
Number five, bargaining and negotiating with Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Number six, allurements and temptations,
Number seven, setting challenges,
Number eight, putting Muhammadﷺ under pressure.
Number nine, jealousy and hatred,
Number ten, persecution,
and Eleven assassination attempts.
So, In Sha Allah(إن شاءالله) we'll start with, Number one: Mockery.
Allahسبحانه وتعالى says,
وَإِذَا رَأَوْكَ إِنْ يَتَّخِذُونَكَ إِلَّا هُزُوًا أَهَٰذَا الَّذِي بَعَثَ اللَّهُ رَسُولًا۝
When they see you they ridicule you and say Is this the one whom Allah has sent as a Messenger.
They were saying, didn't Allah find anyone else to send, I mean, there was no one better to send except you?
So, they would make fun of Rasool Allah ﷺ, they would mock at him.
Now even though, Rasool Allah ﷺ belong to the noblest family, he had the most outstanding character in Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
But because he wasn't the wealthiest, because he wasn't the most powerful, they made fun of him.
People are attracted to the ones, who have wealth, and the ones, who have power.
And there's precedence in this, when the Banni Israel(بني إسرائيل) and the stories mentioned in Surah Al-Baqarah(سورة البقره),
when Banni Israel(بني إسرائيل) went to their Prophet and they said:
We want you to appoint a king over us so that we could fight in Jihad(جهاد).
The King appointed Talut(طالوت),
the Nabi(نبي) appointed Talut(طالوت) to be a king and their leader.
They refused, even though they are the ones, who asked the Nabi(نبي) to appoint for them when the Nabi(نبي) appointed,
they rejected and refused to accept, the leadership of Talut(طالوت).
Why?
They said,
وَلَمْ يُعْطَ سَاعَتً امِنَ الْمَالْ
that he doesn't have a lot of money, he's not wealthy,
اَنَّ يَكُوْنُوْ لَهُ الْمُلْكُ عَلَيْنَا وَنَحْنُ اَحَقُّ بِالُمُلْكِ مِنْهْ وَلَمْ يُعْطَ سَاعَتً امِنَ الْمَالْ
Two things, they said: he is not wealthy.
وَنَحْنُ اَحَقُّ بِالُمُلْكِ مِنْهْ
And there are people more prominent among us to be kings.
And when Rasool Allah ﷺ went to At-Taef(ألطائف)
and we'll talk about his story in At-Taef(ألطائف)
one of the men of At-Taef(ألطائف) told Muhammadﷺ,
didn't Allah find anyone better than you to send as a Prophet.
So, they would mock at Muhammadﷺ and they would make fun of him.
The second form or the second response,
that the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) showed, was insulting and harming Muhammadﷺ.
In Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم) Abu Hurairahرضي الله عنه narrates the story:
Abu Jahal(ابوجهل), he came to some of the leaders of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), who were sitting next to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) and he told them,
are you allowing Muhammad(محمد) to rub his face in the dirt?
That was his evil way of saying Sujood(سجود).
Are you allowing Muhammad(محمد) to rub his face in the dirt?
If I see him do that, I will trample his neck.
If I see him do that I will trample over his neck and I will rub his face in the dirt.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ did come and he started to pray and Rasool Allah ﷺ would pray publicly in front of anyone.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ was praying right there in front of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) and Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) and his friends saw this.
So, Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) stood up to go and fulfill his threat.
So, he walked up to Muhammadﷺ and Muhammadﷺ was in Sujood(سجود)
and suddenly they saw Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) falling back and he was waving with his hands,
like someone who's trying to repulse a danger that is about to befall him.
So, Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) came back and they told him, what happened to you, what was wrong?
He says; What do you mean what happened.! Didn't you see what happened?
They said, no we didn't, there was nothing, all what we saw is, you falling on your back and, waving your hands.
Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) said: There was a trench in front of me, and there was fire and wings and terror.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Those were the angels, if he would have came any closer to me, they would have torn him into pieces.
So, he saw that but everybody else didn't.
All what they saw was, Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) retreating.
And Rasool Allah ﷺ said: those were the angels they would have torn him into pieces, if he came any closer.
Uqba Bin Abi Moyait(عقبة بن ابي معيت), one day came to Rasool Allah ﷺ next to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
And you would notice that most of these events occur next to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) because that is where Rasool Allah ﷺ would pray publicly.
And they would always try to stop him from doing that.
So, Uqba Bin Abi Moyait(عقبة بن ابي معيت) walked up to Muhammadﷺ
and he grabbed his clothes and he started wrapping them around the neck of Rasool Allah ﷺ, trying to choke him
until, Abu Bakrرضي الله عنه stepped in and pushed Uqba Bin Abi Moyait(عقبة بن ابي معيت) away.
And he said: Do you want to kill a man just because he says my lord is Allah.
اَتُرِيْدُوْنَ اَنْ تَقْتُلُوْنَ رَجُلً اَنْ يَقًوْلَ رَبِّيَ الله
The reason why you want to kill him is because he's saying my lord is Allah
and he pushed Uqba Bin Abi Moyait(عقبة بن ابي معيت) away.
Now for some people, they don't mind being hurt, or cursed or humiliated.
Some people naturally have thick skin, I mean, they're not sensitive at all.
But the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah صلوات الله وسلام عليه, they were very sensitive, and they had a lot of dignity.
So, such things hurt them and harm them a lot.
And the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah, they all had very respectable personalities.
So, when such things happened, I mean, these are very, very insulting events to them.
And this was hurting Rasool Allah ﷺ a lot, but he would continue with his Da'wah(دعوة) and go on,
and he would follow, what Allahسبحانه وتعالى told him.
وَأَعْرِضْ عَنِ الْجَاهِلِينَ۝
Just ignore the ignorant, ignore them.
Rasool Ullah would not respond to them, would not fight with them, he would go on with his work.
Another incident that was narrated by Al-Bukhari(اَلْبُخَارِيْ),
Rasool Allah ﷺ again was praying next to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) and Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) came to the leaders of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
who would always meet and sit, next to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
And he told them, so and so has slaughtered a camel,
who will go and pick up the contents of the abdomen of the camel, and dump it on Rasool Allah ﷺ in Salah(صلاة).
So, the most evil among them, Uqba Bin Abi Moyait(عقبة بن ابي معيت), he picked up the challenge
and he went and grabbed all of the insides of the abdomen, the intestines and the stomach, and he carried it.
And he waited until Rasool Allah ﷺ was in the position of Sujood(سجود), and he dumped it over him.
Rasool Allah ﷺ continued with his Sujood(سجود) as if nothing happened.
And then his daughter Fatima رضي الله عنها, saw what happened to her father.
And by the way, it's very hurting to children to see their parents being humiliated,
And psychiatrists in Falastein(فلسطين),
they say that this is affecting the psychology of the children in Falastein(فلسطين),
when they see their fathers and their mothers abused and kicked and hit by Israeli soldiers.
So, you have an entire generation of children, who are growing up seeing their parents going through all of this abuse.
And the psychiatrist was saying that it leaves some very dangerous marks and scars on their personalities.
I mean, especially for children, it's very detrimental for them to see their parents go through humiliation.
So, Fatima رضي الله عنها she saw this happening to her father,
and her father continued in Sujood(سجود), so she ran up to him
and she started taking all of that dirt from the shoulders of her father.
Rasool Allah ﷺ when he finished his Salaah(صلاة).
He made a Dua(دُعَا) and he did Dua(دُعَا) publicly in front of the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
He said: O Allah punish Abu Jahal(ابوجهل)
and Utba Bin Rabiya(عتبة بن ربيعه)
and Shaybah Bin Rabiya(شيبة بن ربيعه),
Al-Waleed Bin Utbah(الوليد بن عتبة),
Ummayyah Bin Khalaf(امية بن خلف)
and Uqba Bin Abi Moyait(عقبة بن ابي معيت).
He made Dua(دُعَا) against seven
I counted six.
The seventh Abdullah Bin Masood(عبدالله بن مسعود), the narrator of the Hadith(حديث) said I forgot, who was the seventh.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ made Dua(دُعَا) against them,
and this was a very rare thing that Rasool Allah ﷺ would make Dua(دُعَا) against some people.
But it's got so bad that Rasool Allah ﷺ was so hurt
he made Dua(دُعَا) against them, and he made Dua(دُعَا) in front of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
Abdullah Bin Masood(عبدالله بن مسعود) said,
I have seen with my own eyes, all of these men killed in the Battle of Badr(بدر),
all of them.
That was the fulfillment of the Dua(دُعَا) of Rasool Allah ﷺ , they all died on Kufr(كفر).
Now, I just gave a few examples, but there are many other examples that one could go through that illuminate this point further.
Number three,
Accusing the Prophet ﷺ, or what we could refer to as character assassination.
They would try to attack the character of the messenger to destroy the message.
So, they would accuse Rasool Allah ﷺ of being a magician,
وَقَالُوا يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِي نُزِّلَ عَلَيْهِ الذِّكْرُ إِنَّكَ لَمَجْنُونٌ۝
They said: O you who is receiving the revelation, you are insane.
وَقَالَو سَاحِرٌ كَذَّابٌ۝
They said: He's a magician, and a liar and they said he's a soothsayer, Kahin(كاهن).
They used whatever slandering terms they could use.
They'd just throw them at Rasool Allah ﷺ, in order to assassinate the character of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And the purpose of that is to destroy the message itself, because Allahسبحانه وتعالى says,
قَدْ نَعْلَمُ إِنَّهُ لَيَحْزُنُكَ الَّذِي يَقُولُونَ ۖ
فَإِنَّهُمْ لَا يُكَذِّبُونَكَ وَلَٰكِنَّ الظَّالِمِينَ بِآيَاتِ اللَّهِ يَجْحَدُونَ۝
They do not disbelieve you, but they are rejecting the signs of Allah.
Allahسبحانه وتعالى is saying that they don't really have a problem with you.
They do not disbelieve you, deep in their hearts, they know that you are the truthful and the honest.
But it is because they want to reject the message, they are attacking you.
So, all of these attacks that you are receiving is not because of your character, it is because of the religion.
And this will take us back to the words of Warqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل), in the early days he told Muhammadﷺ, you will be driven out of your land.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Me, they will drive me out of my land.?
Rasool Allah ﷺ knew that he was so admired and loved by the people of Makkah,
he couldn't imagine how one day they will drive him out of his land.
But then Warqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل) said: Anyone who would present his people with a message similar to yours,
would be fought he will have enemies.
So, it's not you it is the message.
So, now they were accusing Muhammadﷺ, in order to block the message.
Rasool Allah ﷺ would go into the marketplace and the marketplaces in Makkah served not only as a place for doing business,
but that's where they would hold their fairs, I'll just give the meaning of it.
They would have competitions in poetry, and they would have competitions in speeches,
they would hold those competitions in these marketplaces.
So, the marketplace wasn't strictly for business but it was also the cultural center.
That's where the speakers would come, it's sort of like Hyde Park
speakers from all over the world would go, and just congregate there.
Although it was a difference, I mean in Hyde park you don't necessarily get the best but in Souq Akaaz(سوق اعكاظ) you will get the best,
the best speakers of Arabia would go to Souq Akaaz(سوق اعكاظ)
and they would present their works, their poetry and their speeches.
And the best of these poems will be hang on the wall of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه),
they are called Al-Muallaqaat(ألمعلقات), the hanged poems.
Rasool Allah ﷺ would enter these marketplaces and speak to the masses.
In this Hadith(حديث) narrated by Imam Al-Ahmad(امام الاحمد).
Rabiya Bin Haddad(ربيعه بن حداد), he says that
I saw the Messenger of Allah in the Market of Zul-Majaaz(ذوالمجاز) or the fair of Zul-Majaaz(ذوالمجاز).
And he was saying, O, you people say there is no God but Allah and you would prosper.
That was his message to the people say:
لا اله الا الله تُفْلِحُوْ
Say there is no God but Allah and you would be successful.
And he would repeat that message again and again and walk and meet different people.
Now, Rabiyyah(ربيعة) said: There was a man following him.
And whoever Rasool Allah ﷺ would speak to, this man would go and speak to, and say;
"Don't believe him, he's a liar"
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ would go and speak to a group of people and tell them say;
لا اله الا الله
you would succeed.
When Rasool Allah leaves Abu Lahab(أبو لهب) would come in, and tell the same people,
"Don't believe him, he's a liar."
Now, Rabiya Bin Haddad(ربيعه بن حداد) said: I asked who that man was.
They said, this is his Uncle Abu Lahab(أبو لهب).
Rabiya Bin Haddad(ربيعه بن حداد) wasn't from Makkah.
He said, I asked who that man was?
They said; This is his uncle.
Imagine how difficult this is, Abu Lahab(أبو لهب) is unwinding whatever was been winded, by Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Whatever Rasool Allah ﷺ would do, Abu Lahab(أبو لهب) would go behind him and destroy it.
We gain encouragement, by seeing the fruits of our efforts.
We have to be rewarded one way or another otherwise, we wouldn't have motivation to go on.
In our work, unless there's some kind of reward, it would be impossible for us to work.
And we are rewarded in different forms, one of them is financial
you're being paid for what you do.
Other forms of reward is recognition.
Third form of reward is support that you would get from workers or your leaders.
But it will be impossible to go on, if everything is against you at your work.
And what keeps you going is seeing the fruits of your efforts.
I mean, imagine that we arrange this course and it doesn't work out.
And then we try to arrange it again a month later and it doesn't work out, nobody shows up.
Imagine just they try it again next month, no one shows up.
They try it again, third time no one shows up do you think they will have the spirit to continue doing this again and again,
it becomes really difficult.
Rasool Allah ﷺ and some of the many of the other Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء)
they would continue doing the same thing again and again and nothing would happen.
And Noahعليه السّلام for example.
He's giving his people Da'wah(دعوة) day and night publicly and privately with no response, no response, whatsoever.
He's seeing no fruits of his efforts at all.
That's very difficult, especially when we're talking about 950 years.
Rasool Allah ﷺ in Makkah is going and speaking to these people who don't know him.
He's speaking to foreigners, and this fair of Zul Majaz(ذوالمجاز) and Aakaaz(أعكاظ).
And as soon as he speaks to the people, someone comes and distorts his reputation by saying, he's a liar.
Nevertheless, Rasool Allah ﷺ, had the encouragement to continue and speak to the people and go on and on, neglecting what his uncle was doing to him,
especially in the society of Arabia, where there's seniority.
I mean, what can Rasool Allah ﷺ do to stop his uncle.
So, he would just leave him alone and continue with his Da'wah(دعوة).
And in another narration it says that Abu Lahab(أبو لهب) would go on and tell the people.
O people, let not this man, entice you away from your religion, the religion of your forefathers.
And this was narrated by Al-Bayhaqi(ألبيهقي).
Another example narrated by Al-Bayhaqi(ألبيهقي) and Al-Hakim(الحاكم);
Right before the season of Hajj(حج), Al-Waleed Bin Mugheera(الوليد بن مغيره), who was the elder of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) at that time,
he addressed a meeting of the leaders of the community.
And he told them, that the season of Hajj(حَجْ) is approaching, pilgrimage.
And the delegations of the Arabs are going to start pouring in.
Let's unify our opinion regarding disassociate of yours and let's not contradict each other.
What Al-Waleed Bin Mugheera(الوليد بن مغيره) is referring to here?
Is that the season of pilgrimage is coming and the Arabs are going to start coming to Makkah,
and Muhammadﷺ will be visiting them and speaking to them.
We don't want to contradict each other in our opinion regarding him.
So, we don't want some people saying that he is a liar, some people saying is a magician, some people saying is this soothsayer
we have to have a unified opinion in order to go to the people and warn them from this man.
So, the people said, you tell us what you think, we'll abide by it.
Al-Waleed Bin Mugheera(الوليد بن مغيره) said: I want to hear from you.
They said: We'll claim that he's a soothsayer.
He responded, No! He is no soothsayer,
I have seen soothsayers and he doesn't engage in the rhymed mumbling Doug rail they use.
People are not going to believe you, if you say that he's a soothsayer.
They said: Well, let's say that he is crazy, possessed by spirits.
He said: He is not crazy.
We have seen and known those, who are crazy.
And he has none of their choking, erratic movement and mumbling.
He doesn't show the signs of people who are insane or obsessed by Jinn(جن).
They said: Well, let's claim that he is a poet.
He said: No, he's no poet.
We know poetry, in all its symmetrical forms and what he speaks is not poetry.
Al-Waleed Bin Mugheera(الوليد بن مغيره) in another narration says, I am the most expert among you, in poetry,
I know all of its forms, and Qur'an is not poetry.
They said: Let's claim that he is a sorcerer.
He said: No! He is no sorcerer, we've seen sorcerers and their magic, and he doesn't do any of their tying and untying.
So, basically, they mentioned all, what they have
and Al-Waleed Bin Mugheera(الوليد بن مغيرة) is saying that this won't make sense.
Eventually, they said;
Well, what are we gonna say.
So, he thought about it for a while and then he came back and said,
well, let's just say that he's a sorcerer.
Before that he said: By God, there is splendor in what he speaks
in essence, he is like a palm tree, whose branches give much fruit.
All you have been saying will not be believed.
The closest thing is for you, to say,
This man is a sorcerer, who comes between a man and his religion,
a man and his father,
a man and his wife,
a man and his brother,
and a man and his tribe.
That's the closest that we can come to agree on that he's a sorcerer.
That is when Allah سبحانه وتعالى revealed the Ayaat(آيات)
ذَرْنِي وَمَنْ خَلَقْتُ وَحِيدًا۝
وَجَعَلْتُ لَهُ مَالًا مَمْدُودًا۝
وَبَنِينَ شُهُودًا۝
وَمَهَّدْتُ لَهُ تَمْهِيدًا۝
ثُمَّ يَطْمَعُ أَنْ أَزِيدَ۝
كَلَّا ۖ إِنَّهُ كَانَ لِآيَاتِنَا عَنِيدًا۝
سَأُرْهِقُهُ صَعُودًا ۝
إِنَّهُ فَكَّرَ وَقَدَّرَ ۝
فَقُتِلَ كَيْفَ قَدَّرَ ۝
ثُمَّ قُتِلَ كَيْفَ قَدَّرَ ۝
ثُمَّ نَظَرَ  ۝
ثُمَّ عَبَسَ وَبَسَرَ ۝
ثُمَّ أَدْبَرَ وَاسْتَكْبَرَ ۝َ
فَقَالَ إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا سِحْرٌ يُؤْثَرُ۝
Verily, he thought and plotted.
So, let him be cursed, how he plotted.
And once more, let him be cursed how he plotted.
Then he thought, then he fround and he looked in a bad tempered way.
Then he turned back and was proud.
Then he said, this is nothing but magic from that of old.
This is nothing but the word of a human being.
These Ayaat(آيات) are in Surah Al-Mudassir(سورة ألمدثر).
Number four: Deforming the message.
An-Nadhar Bin Hariss(النضر بن حارث), he went to Persia, specifically to learn stories.
He went all the way to Persia to learn stories.
He came back and whenever he would see Rasool Allah ﷺ sitting with a group of people.
He would call the people and call others and say: Come to me, I have better stories to tell.
My stories are better.
And he was saying it's all about stories, what Muhammadﷺ is speaking about the past all of this, these are just fables, tales.
I have something better to offer.
Allah سبحانه وتعالى says;
وَقَالُوا أَسَاطِيرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ اكْتَتَبَهَا
فَهِيَ تُمْلَىٰ عَلَيْهِ بُكْرَةً وَأَصِيلًا۝
They claim that these are stories or Tales of the past.
So, they wanted to say that this is just storytelling, tales that are fabricated, untrue.
Who knows what happened to Musaعليه السّلام, who knows what happened to Eesa(عيسى), who knows what happened to the other Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء).
He's just telling you stories.
There is no basis of what he is narrating to you.
Number five: Bargaining and negotiations;
The people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) came to Muhammadﷺ and said;
Let's make a deal.
We will agree to worship Allah for one day and you worship our gods for another day.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told them, I would never agree to do such a thing.
They came back to him sometime later, and they said: We have a better offer to make.
We will worship Allah for a week, and you worship our gods for one day.
He said: No.
Came back again, we have a better offer to make.
We will worship Allah for a month and you just give us one day.
Rasool Ullah said: No
Allah سبحانه وتعالى revealed the Ayah(آية).
وَدُّوا لَوْ تُدْهِنُ فَيُدْهِنُونَ۝
They would wish that you would compromise, so that they can compromise with you.
Their religion is manmade, they could compromise in it, they can change it.
It's okay for them to worship Allah for a day and their gods for another day.
It's fine, it's a man made religion, there's no control on it.
But Rasool Allah ﷺ is receiving Wahee(وحي) from Allah, he cannot change it.
So, he cannot compromise in the message.
The message doesn't change.
Even if you worship Allah for a year, I'm not going to give you one day.
I'm not going to give you a day in my whole life.
قُلْ يَا أَيُّهَا الْكَافِرُونَ۝
لَا أَعْبُدُ مَا تَعْبُدُونَ۝
O you, disbelievers, I am not gonna worship what you worship, neither are you going to worship, what I worship.
لَكُمْ دِينُكُمْ وَلِيَ دِينِ۝
You have your way and I have mine
And they tried all different ways of bargaining, it would never work with Muhammadﷺ.
Now they would become upset because this is something that, they could afford to do
and they were wondering how come Rasool Allah ﷺ can't do it.
Why do we have to always keep on compromising and bargaining and he is not reciprocating.
And that was a cause of obviously that aggravated them further.
But Muhammad ﷺ was telling them that I am just a conveyor of a message.
It is not from myself, it is from Allah.
6; Allurements and temptations, and Number Seven, Setting Challenges,
This following narration points out to both number six and seven.
It's a narration by Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ),
Ibn Abbasرضي الله عنه said that the leaders from Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) met
and they were next to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) and they said let's send for Muhammad(محمد) and speak with him.
And we want to exhaust all different ways and we don't want to give him any excuse.
Let's try everything with him.
So, they sent someone to call Muhammadﷺ.
Ibn Abbas(ابن عباس) says; that Muhammadﷺ came rushing, he was eager to come and meet with the leaders
because he thought there might be a change of heart.
Maybe now they want to respond, maybe they're willing to soften their stance.
So, he came to them in a hurry.
When he arrived there, Utba(عتبه) started speaking to Muhammadﷺ,
actually Utba(عتبه) was one of them, but there were many around all of the leaders.
They told Muhammad صلوات الله وسلام عليه
O Muhammad(محمد), we sent for you to reconcile with you.
So, it started with this very nice statement.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ was getting an impression that finally they're softening.
They said: O Muhammad, we sent for you to reconcile with you,
by God, we know of no Arab man who has ever brought his people as much trouble as you have.
You have reviled the forbearers, criticize the religion,
ridiculed the values, cursed the gods, and divided our community.
Every unpleasant thing possible you have done to make a rift, between you and us.
In another narration, they said: We have never seen a person, who has brought so much evil on his people like you have.
And now they're starting to throw out the temptations to Muhammadﷺ.
They said: O Muhammad(محمد) if you are presenting us with this message,
because you are in need of money, we will collect for you money, until we make you the wealthiest among us.
O Muhammad(محمد), If you are coming up with this religion, because you are seeking power,
we will appoint you as a king over us.
O Muhammad(محمد), If you are presenting us with this religion, because you are desiring women,
we will choose for you the best 10 women in Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and marry them all to you.
O Muhammad(محمد), if you are presenting us with this message, because you are obsessed with devils, demons;
We will spend whatever is needed to cure you, even if we have to exhaust all of our wealth in the process.
Tell us what you want?
Rasool Allah ﷺ responded and said, what you have said, does not apply to me.
I have not brought to you my message seeking your money, nor honor among you, nor sovereignty over you.
God has sent me to you as a messenger
He has revealed the document to me and has ordered me to bring you good news and warn you.
I have brought you a message from my Lord, and I've given you counsel.
If you accept what I've brought to you, then that is for your good on earth, and in the hereafter,
if you reject it, I will await God's decision, until he decides between myself and you.
These are the approximate words of Muhammadﷺ.
They said: Alright, if you are turning down all of our offers
then, you know how narrow our land is.
You know, for those of you have seen Makkah.
Makkah is very narrow valleys surrounded by mountains you know, mountains all over.
And it's a very rough environment, the weather of it and all of these mountains, and it is very narrow.
So, they said: O Muhammad(محمد), you know how narrow our land is,
and how poor we are, and how difficult our life is.
So, how about you go to your Lord, who has sent you,
and you tell him to move these mountains away,
just level them and give us more space and land.
And then why don't you ask him to make some rivers flow in Makkah, like the rivers of Syria and Iraq.
We want to have some rivers like other people have.
And then we want you also to go to your Lord and to tell Him to bring back to life, some of our forefathers.
And we want you to bring back to life Qusa'e Bin Kulaab(قصئ بن كلاب) because he was a truth telling Shaikh(شيخ).
And we want to ask him, if what you are saying is true or not.
And then Muhammad(محمد) if you do that, and our forefathers, agree to what you say, then will follow you.
Muhammadﷺ responded and said, this is not why I have been sent.
I have only brought you from God what He has sent me with,
I have informed you of what I was sent to convey to you, If you accept it
then that is your good fortune on earth, and in the hereafter.
If you reject it, I must wait patiently for God's decree and for him to judge between us.
They continued and they said: Well, how about if you then, ask your Lord
to send down an angel, who will witness to your truth
and also we want you to ask him to give us some castles, gardens, treasures of gold and silver.
And then how about you do this?
Why don't you tell Him to fulfill your needs because we see that you are seeking a livelihood just like we are, you doing business.
Now, if you are so close to your God
why don't you tell him to give you some wealth, so that we'll know how prestigious you are, in His eyes.
That is if you're claiming to be a messenger,
how come you're just like every one of us, you going and working.
Tell your Lord if He loves you to give you some Wealth.
Again, Rasool Allah ﷺ said: I'm not going to do so,
I am not the one to ask such things of His Lord.
That is not why I have been sent to you
God has sent me to announce and warn.
If you accept my message then that is your good fortune here on Earth and in the Afterlife.
If you reject it then I must be patient and leave the matter up to God,
until He decides between myself and you.
They said: Well, then fine.
Ask your Lord to bring down the punishment that you have been promising us.
Come on! Let him bring the sky upon our heads right now.
Show us if you can.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: That is up to God, if, He wishes, He will do that to you.
They commented and said: O Muhammad(محمد), doesn't your Lord know these questions that we're going to ask you?
How come is not helping you and giving you an answer.
We know who's teaching you all of this.
You are being taught this Qur'an of yours, by a man in Yamamah(يمامه) called Ar-Rahman(الرحمن).
And we're never gonna believe in that man called Ar-Rahman(الرحمن).
All of it, just fabricating lies one over another,
this man in Yamamah(يمامه) called Ar-Rahman(الرحمن), something they made up and fabricated.
One of them said: We worship the angels who are God's daughters,
another said: we will not believe you till you bring us God and the angels beforehand.
It's all mockery and insults, and then they left.
One of them came back, to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
So, one might think that this man, Abdullah Bin Umayyah(عبدالله بن أمية) felt sorry for what happened.
And maybe you wanted to come and apologize
Or maybe he wanted to come and become Muslim.
Specially that he is a cousin of Rasool Allah ﷺ, his mother is Rasool Ullah's aunt.
Well, Abdullah Bin Umayyah(عبدالله بن أميه) came to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said:
O Muhammad(محمد), your people have offered you the best offers, and you turned them down.
And then they asked you to perform miracles for them, and you refused.
They asked you to bring down punishment on them, and you didn't.
Now I'll tell you what?
I'm not gonna believe in you, until you bring a ladder that goes all the way up to the heaven.
And then you climb it, while I'm watching you,
and you go up to God, to Allah,
and you asked him to write down for you a letter,
stating that you are His Prophet, and have Him sign it,
and then we want that document to come down accompanied by four angels,
to be witnesses that you are a messenger from God.
And then you know what, even if you do that
I think I'm not gonna believe in you, Dead End!!!
Nothing is going to work with these people.
وَإِنْ يَرَوْا كُلَّ آيَةٍ لَا يُؤْمِنُوا بِهَا
If they see every sign they won't believe.
This was the environment Rasool Allah ﷺ was working in, dealing with these type of people.
It's a Dead End you can go any further, whatever you're going to do, I'm telling you beforehand, I'm not gonna believe.
Even if Allah sends down a message from Him personally with four angels to witness it, it's not going to be enough.
Rasool Allah ﷺ went back home, he was regretful,
at the failure to achieve what he had expected from his people
because he went with all of his good expectation, that now my people have changed.
That was the impression he got when they invited him.
And then suddenly he was turned down in this ruthless fashion.
صَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ